

M. Murat Ardag

♀ 10715 Berlin



Cypriot (EU). British Overseas & Turkish



I am a data scientist and a political psychologist (Ph.D.) with a background in psychometrics, psycholinguistics, cross-cultural research, and modeling subjectivity. My domain expertise is particularly relevant to political consulting, targeted communication and public administration.

Data Science

2+ years **?**: pandas, numpy, scikitlearn, matplotlib, seaborn

7+ years **Q**: tidyverse, tidymodels, easystats, lavaan (& its ecosystem), psychometric networks (collection of packages), bnlearn, quanteda (& its ecosystem), spacy, igraph, infer, survival, survminer, rstanarm, rjags Since 2021 Tensorflow-Keras.

pytorch, prophet

Machine Learning

Regression, classification, time series, natural language processing

Statistics

The general structural equation modeling framework, psychometric networks, Bayesian networks, social network analysis, Survival analysis, Bayesian inference

Programming

Since 2021 Git, Bash

Databases

Since 2021 Postgres, SQLite,

MongoDB

Deployment

Since 2021 AWS (EC2, RDS), Docker,

Flask

SELECTED PROJECTS

Attitudes towards COVID-19 and Voting Intention in Germany

Machine and deep learning, psychometrics

Measuring Organizational Practices

Natural language processing

Movie Recommender

Unsupervised machine learning

Dockerized Data Pipeline

🚺 Involves: MongoDB, ETL job (sentiment analysis), Postgres & Slackbot

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

02/2019 - 12/2021 Researcher

Bremen International School of Social Sciences.

Psychology & Methods,

Jacobs University, Bremen, Germany

07/2012 - 02/2020 (Interim-) Academic Coordinator & Research Assistant

Lecturer

Social Sciences Department,

European Master in Migration and Intercultural Relations

CvO Universität Oldenburg, Oldenburg, Germany

EDUCATION

2021 Data Science Bootcamp

Spiced Academy, Berlin, Germany

2015 - 2018 Ph.D. in Political Science

CvO Universität Oldenburg, Oldenburg, Germany

2008 - 2012 M.A. in Political Science

Bilkent University, Ankara, Turkey

2005 - 2008 M.A. in International Relations

Galatasaray University, Istanbul, Turkey

LANGUAGES

English (Proficient), German (Intermediate), Turkish

(Native)

INTERESTS

Drumming, cycling, cooking